Guide to the Giant Food Stores Advertising Collection, 1951-2001
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Microfilm Series, 1967-1993, (393 reels)
  - Microfilm: Advertisements
    - Washington, D.C.: Post--Competition advertising, 1972 Oct.-Dec., MF-O-211
    - Washington, D.C.: Post--Competition advertising, 1973 Jan.-Mar., MF-O-212
    - Washington, D.C.: Post--Competition advertising, 1973 Apr.-June, MF-O-213
    - Washington, D.C.: Post--Competition advertising, 1973 July-Sept., MF-O-214
    - Washington, D.C.: Post--Competition advertising, 1973 Oct.-Dec., MF-O-215
    - Washington, D.C.: Post--Competition advertising, 1974 Jan.-Mar., MF-O-216
    - Washington, D.C.: Post--Competition advertising, 1974 Apr.-June, MF-O-217
    - Washington, D.C.: Post--Competition advertising, 1974 July-Sept., MF-O-218
    - Washington, D.C.: Post--Competition advertising, 1974 Oct.-Dec., MF-O-219
    - Washington, D.C.: Post--Competition advertising, 1975 Jan.-Mar., MF-O-220
    - Washington, D.C.: Post--Competition advertising, 1975 Apr.-June, MF-O-221
    - Washington, D.C.: Post--Competition advertising, 1975 July-Sept., MF-O-222
    - Washington, D.C.: Post--Competition advertising, 1975 Oct.-Dec., MF-O-223
    - Washington, D.C.: Post--Competition advertising, 1976 Jan.-Mar., MF-O-224
    - Washington, D.C.: Post--Competition advertising, 1979 July 9-Aug. 29, MF-O-225
    - Washington, D.C.: Post--Competition advertising, 1979 Aug. 30-Dec., MF-O-226
    - Washington, D.C.: Post--Giant + Competition, 1979 Aug.-Dec., MF-O-227
    - Washington, D.C.: Post and Star, 1979 July 10-Aug. 29, MF-O-228
    - Washington, D.C.: Star, 1976 Apr.-July, MF-O-229
    - Multiple cities: Baltimore News American, Frederick News, Frederick Post, Salisbury Times, 1983 Oct.-Dec., MF-O-230
    - Multiple cities: Baltimore News American, Frederick News, Frederick Post, 1983 Jan.-June, MF-O-231
    - Multiple cities: Baltimore Sun, Frederick News, Frederick Post, Fredericksburg Free Lance-Star, 1980 Jan.-June, MF-O-232
  - Microfilm: Circulars
    - 1968 Mar.-Oct., MF-O-233
    - 1968 Oct.-1969 Sept., MF-O-234
    - 1973 July 9-Sept 24, MF-O-235
    - 1980 May-July, MF-O-236
    - 1980 Aug.-Oct., MF-O-237
    - 1980 Nov.-Dec., MF-O-238
    - 1981 Jan.-Mar., MF-O-239
    - 1981 Apr.-Sept., MF-O-240
    - 1981 Oct.-Dec., MF-O-241
    - 1982 Jan.-Mar., MF-O-242
    - 1982 Apr.-Sept., MF-O-243
    - 1982 Oct.-Dec., MF-O-244
    - 1983 Jan.-Mar., MF-O-245
    - 1983 Apr.-June (1 of 2), MF-O-246
    - 1983 Apr.-June (2 of 2), MF-O-247
    - 1983 Oct.-Dec., MF-O-248
    - 1984 Jan.-Mar., MF-O-249
    - 1984 Apr.-June, MF-O-250
    - 1984 July-Sept., MF-O-251
    - 1984 Oct.-Dec (1 of 2), MF-O-252
    - 1984 Oct.-Dec (2 of 2), MF-O-253
    - 1985 Jan.-Mar (1 of 2), MF-O-254
    - 1985 Jan.-Mar (2 of 2), MF-O-255
    - 1985 July-Sept., MF-O-256
    - 1985 Oct.-Dec., MF-O-257
    - 1986 Jan.-Feb., MF-O-258
    - 1986 Mar., MF-O-259
    - 1986 Apr.-June, MF-O-260
    - 1986 May-July, MF-O-261
    - 1986 Aug., MF-O-262
    - 1986 Sept.-Dec., MF-O-263
    - 1987 Jan.-Mar., MF-O-264
    - 1987 Mar.-May, MF-O-265
    - 1987 June, MF-O-266
    - 1987 June-July, MF-O-267
    - 1987 Aug.-Sept., MF-O-268
    - 1987 Sept.-Nov., MF-O-269
    - 1987 Nov.-Dec., MF-O-270
    - 1988 Jan., MF-O-271
    - 1988 Jan.-Mar., MF-O-272
    - 1988 Mar.-Apr., MF-O-273
    - 1988 May-June, MF-O-274
    - 1988 June-July, MF-O-275
    - 1988 July-Sept., MF-O-276
    - 1988 Sept.-Oct., MF-O-277
    - 1988 Oct.-Nov., MF-O-278
    - 1988 Nov.-Dec., MF-O-279
    - 1989 Jan., MF-O-280
    - 1989 Feb., MF-O-281
    - 1989 Mar., MF-O-282
    - 1989 Apr., MF-O-283
    - 1989 May, MF-O-284
    - 1989 June, MF-O-285
    - 1989 July, MF-O-286
    - 1989 Aug 6-19, MF-O-287
    - 1989 Aug 20-Sept 9, MF-O-288
    - 1989 Sept 10-Oct 7, MF-O-289
    - 1989 Oct 8-29, MF-O-290
    - 1989 Oct 29-Nov 25, MF-O-291
    - 1989 Nov 26-Dec 17, MF-O-292
    - 1989 Dec 18-31, MF-O-293
    - 1990 Jan 7-28, MF-O-294
    - 1990 Jan 28-Feb 17, MF-O-295
    - 1990 Feb 18-Mar 11, MF-O-296
    - 1990 Mar.-Apr., MF-O-297
    - 1990 Apr (1 of 2), MF-O-298
    - 1990 Apr (2 of 2), MF-O-299
    - 1990 May, MF-O-300
    - 1990 June, MF-O-301
    - 1990 July (1 of 2), MF-O-302
    - 1990 July (2 of 2), MF-O-303
    - 1990 Aug., MF-O-304
    - 1990 Sept (1 of 2), MF-O-305
    - 1990 Sept (2 of 2), MF-O-306
    - 1990 Oct., MF-O-307
    - 1990 Nov., MF-O-308
    - 1990 Dec (1 of 2), MF-O-309
    - 1990 Dec (2 of 2), MF-O-310
    - 1991 Jan., MF-O-311
    - 1991 Feb., MF-O-312
    - 1991 Mar., MF-O-313
    - 1991 Mar.-Apr., MF-O-314
    - 1991 Apr.-May, MF-O-315
    - 1991 May, MF-O-316
    - 1991 June 2-16, MF-O-317
    - 1991 June 23-30, MF-O-318
    - 1991 July 17-21, MF-O-319
    - 1991 July 28-Aug 11, MF-O-320
    - 1991 Aug 18-Sept 1, MF-O-321
    - 1991 Sept 8-15, MF-O-322
    - 1991 Sept 22-29, MF-O-323
    - 1991 Oct 6-13, MF-O-324
    - 1991 Oct 20-27, MF-O-325
    - 1991 Nov 3-10, MF-O-326
    - 1991 Nov 17-24, MF-O-327
    - 1991 Dec 1-8, MF-O-328
    - 1991 Dec 15-29, MF-O-329
    - 1992 Jan 5-12, MF-O-330
    - 1992 Jan 19-26, MF-O-331
    - 1992 Feb 2-9, MF-O-332
    - 1992 Feb 16-23, MF-O-333
    - 1992 Mar 1-8, MF-O-334
    - 1992 Mar 15-22, MF-O-335
    - 1992 Mar 29-Apr 5, MF-O-336
    - 1992 Apr 12-18, MF-O-337
    - 1992 Apr 19-26, MF-O-338
    - 1992 May 3-10, MF-O-339
    - 1992 May 17-25, MF-O-340
    - 1992 May 26-30, MF-O-341
    - 1992 May 31-June 6, MF-O-342
    - 1992 June 7-13, MF-O-343
    - 1992 June 14-20, MF-O-344
    - 1992 June 21-27, MF-O-345
    - 1992 June 28-July 4, MF-O-346
    - 1992 July 5-11, MF-O-347
    - 1992 July 12-18, MF-O-348
    - 1992 July 19-25, MF-O-349
    - 1992 July 26-31, MF-O-350
    - 1992 Aug 16-22, MF-O-351
    - 1992 Aug 23-29, MF-O-352
    - 1992 Aug 30, MF-O-353
    - 1992 Sept (1 of 4), MF-O-354
    - 1992 Sept (2 of 4), MF-O-355
    - 1992 Sept (3 of 4), MF-O-356
    - 1992 Sept (4 of 4), MF-O-357
    - 1992 Oct 4-10, MF-O-358
    - 1992 Oct 11-17, MF-O-359
    - 1992 Oct 18-24, MF-O-360
    - 1992 Oct 25-31, MF-O-361
    - 1992 Nov 1-7, MF-O-362
    - 1992 Nov 8-14, MF-O-363
    - 1992 Nov 15-21, MF-O-364
    - 1992 Nov 22-28, MF-O-365
    - 1992 Nov 29-Dec 5, MF-O-366
    - 1992 Dec 6-12, MF-O-367
    - 1992 Dec 13-19, MF-O-368
    - 1992 Dec 20-26, MF-O-369
    - 1992 Dec 27-31, MF-O-370
    - 1993 Jan 3-9, MF-O-371
    - 1993 Jan 10-16, MF-O-372
    - 1993 Jan 17-23, MF-O-373
    - 1993 Jan 24-30, MF-O-374
    - 1993 Jan 31-Feb 6, MF-O-375
    - 1993 Feb 7-13, MF-O-376
    - 1993 Feb 14-20, MF-O-377
    - 1993 Feb 21-27, MF-O-378
    - 1993 Feb 28-Mar 6, MF-O-379
    - 1993 Mar 7-13, MF-O-380
    - 1993 Mar 14-20, MF-O-381
    - 1993 Mar 21-27, MF-O-382
    - 1993 Mar 28-Apr 3, MF-O-383
    - 1993 Apr 4-10, MF-O-384
    - 1993 Apr 11-17, MF-O-385
    - 1993 Apr 18-24, MF-O-386
    - 1993 Apr 25-May 1, MF-O-387
    - 1993 May 2-8, MF-O-388
    - 1993 May 9-15, MF-O-389
    - 1993 May 16-22, MF-O-390
    - 1993 May 23-29, MF-O-391
  - Microfilm: General Merchandise
    - 1967 Jan.-1969 Mar 5, MF-O-392
    - 1967 Jan.-1970 Jan., MF-O-393
- Scrapbooks Series, 1970-1982, (5 boxes)
  Includes eight scrapbooks with fullpage newspaper advertisements, dating from 1970-1982.
  - Advertising Scrapbook, 1970-1973 (Box SB1)
    General fullsize newspaper ads glued or loosely attached to black scrapbook pages. Many feature consumer advocate Esther Peterson, including the following themes:
    Discount pricing, Giant goes discount
    Unit pricing, Goodbye slide rule
    Consumer Bill of Rights
    Recycled paper products
    Giant brand products
    Nutritional labeling, We're making progress
    Beef, You have the right to be informed
    Giant truckers
    Detergents and water pollution
    Welcome Home Mr. President, addressed to President and Mrs. Nixon, 1972 Jun 3
    We love you Melissa, addressed to Olympic swimming champion Melissa Belote, 1973 Sep 15
  - Advertising Scrapbook, 1970-1976
    General fullsize newspaper ads, including the following themes:
    Sugar prices
    Immunization
    Beef
    Halloween
  - Advertising Scrapbook, 1972-1978 (Box SB2)
    General fullsize newspaper ads glued on beige scrapbook pages, post-bound. Including the following themes:
    Discount catalogs and catalog showcase
    Giant department stores and store openings in Bowie, Maryland, 1973
    Going out of business ads for Giant department stores, 1978
    Pants Corral
  - Advertising Scrapbook, 1982
    Fullsize newspaper ads and quarter-page reprints on black scrapbook pages in vinyl, spiral bound book, documenting Somplace Special, Giant Gourmet in McLean, Virginia.
  - Advertising Scrapbook, 1970-1973 (Box SB3)
    General fullsize newspaper ads on black scrapbook pages in vinyl book, including the following themes:
    Seafood
    Dairy
    Prices and government requested price freeze, 1972 Jan 3
    Heidi Bakery
    Open dating
    Open letter to Washington Redskins football team after a victory over the Cowboys, 1971 Oct 6
    Giant truckers, Driving is a civic duty
  - Advertising Scrapbook, 1973-1978 (Box SB4)
    General fullsize newspaper ads on black scrapbook pages, including the following themes:
    Best wishes to President Nixon on inauguration day, 1973
    Open letter to President Nixon, We are grateful...by bringing the peace we have sought... you have earned our gratitude, 1973 Jan 26
    Earth Week
    Maryland lottery, Why we're selling lottery tickets, 1978
    Meat, Yes we have beef, Mystery at the meat counter
  - Advertising Scrapbook, 1973-1978
    Store openings in Alexandria, Baltimore, Frederick
    Pharmacy openings and advertisements
    General seafood ads
    Passover, When the family gathers for a seder, with a list of which stores carry the advertised products
    Store closings, Due to the Maryland Court of Appeals decision on 1973 Jan 2, all Giant Food stores in Maryland will be closed on Sunday
  - Advertising Scrapbook, 1970s (Box SB5)
    General fullsize consumer advocacy newspaper ads and reprints featuring Esther Peterson, on black scrapbook pages in vinyl.
- Oversize Advertisements, (2 boxes)
  Window posters, consumer advocacy newspaper ads, and advertising posters promoting Washington area events, healthy eating and nutrition, Giant store programs and reward systems, and other general advertisements.
  - Window posters (Box OA1)
    Including general advertisements and promotions.
    Now shopping has its rewards
    Don't forget to show your card
    Steering you towards saving
    Save money at Giant with checkout coupons
    Take off with US Air
    Virginia Wine Festival
    Buy Now Play Later/Kings Dominion
    Now Selling Kings Dominion
    Orioles Sweepstakes World Series 1987
    50th Anniversary Ice Capades
    2 for 1 at KB Theatre
    Washington Flower Show
  - Poster boards and newspaper ads (Box OA2)
    Includes 29 window posters on board focusing on healthy eating habits. Many advertise the Eater's Almanac or use the logo from Foods for Health pilot nutrition program between Giant Food and the National Institutes of Health. Also includes unbound fullsize consumer advocacy newspaper ads and advertising posters featuring Esther Peterson and Odonna Matthews:
    We support HR 9178 Office of Consumer Representation, 1977 Oct 30
    Eating right is out of sight
    Bicycle safety
    Nutritional labeling
    Meat, Even the White House can't get filet mignon
    Detergents
    Cycle-Giant label of recycled paper products
    Keep food safe from bacteria
    Eat for health-food and cancer risks
  - Locally Grown Produce window posters on board, each featuring a color photograph of a farmer with their name and location. No Giant logo appears on the board. (Opaperfolder 1)
- Printed Materials, 1994-1998, (2 boxes)
  Includes an incomplete run of Supermarket News, a weekly trade magazine.
  - Supermarket News, 1994, Volume 44: Issues 16-33; 35-36 (Box PM1)
  - Supermarket News, 1995, Volume 45: Issues 6; 21-27; 29-37; 39-47; 50-51
  - Supermarket News, 1996: Volume 46: Issues 1; 3-8; 10-24; 26-28; 30-32
  - Supermarket News, 1996: Volume 46: Issues 33-50; 52 (Box PM2)
  - Supermarket News, 1997, Volume 47: Issues 1-2; 5; 7-19; 21-44; 46; 48-49; 51
  - Supermarket News, 1998, Volume 48: Issue 1